Guide to the Robert Phelan Nazi ephemera collection, 1978-1981
Department of Special Collections
Nazi ephemera collection, 1978-1981,
M0781
Phelan, Robert, collector.
.5 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Organization periodicals, Phelan's correspondence regarding Nazi activities, and ephemera relating to the Nazi movement and other political activities. Includes C.W. Bristol's THE WHITE PRIMER and considerable material from the National Socialist White Worker's Party (NSWWP).
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
None.
Provenance
Purchased, 1994.
Biography
Little biographical information is available on Phelan (c. 1978-1981), and the level and nature of his involvement in Nazi activities is unknown. The materials were aquired by Stanford on June 15, 1994, purchased through a dealer.
Scope and Content
This collection of recent Nazi materials was the property of Robert Phelan, a San Francisco Bay Area resident. It consists of Nazi organization periodicals, Phelan's correspondence regarding Nazi activities, and ephemera relating to the Nazi movement and other political activities.
Access Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Bristol, C.W.; Zundel, Ernst.; Aryan Renaissance Command (ARC); National Socialist Irish Worker's Party (NSIWP); National Socialist Movement.; National Socialist Party U.K. (NSPUK); National Socialist White Worker's Party (NSWWP); Nationalsozialistchen Deutschen.; New Christian Crusace Church.; Society for Individual Rights (SIR); White American Political Association (WAPA); National Socialists.; White supremacy movements.; Auschwitz: Truth or Lie.; The CDL Report.; Christian Vanguard: the Official Publication of the New.; A Gallery of Jewish Types.; The Herald of America.; Historic Testimonial on the Jews.; N.S. News.; N.S. Report.; National Renaissance Bulletin.; National Socialist Bulletin.; The White Primer.; The Newsletter of the White Revolution.; Phoenix.; The Thunderbolt: the White Man's Viewpoit.; White Worker's Bulletin.
Collection Contents
- Phelan's datebook (1972) and miscellaneous addresses and phone numbers (including Ku Klux Klan in Metairie, LA) (Box 1, Folder 1)
- anonymous photo(n.d.) (Box 1, Folder 1)
- envelope addressed to Diane Feinstein with anti-black flyer (Box 1, Folder 1)
- envelope addressed to Quentin Krepp (Box 1, Folder 1)
- copy of letter written by Phelan to Senator Milton Marks(1980) (Box 1, Folder 1)
- Letters from George Blonde1968-1981 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- letter from Society for Individual Rights (SIR), "homophile" organization regarding Phelan's membership (?) (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Aryan Resnaissance Command (ARC)/Bob Spittler (1980-1981), including personal correspondence from Bob Spittler to Phelan (Box 1, Folder 3)
- THE CDL REPORTMarch/April 1981 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- THE NATIONAL RENAISSANCE BULLETIN(April/May 1979 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- National Socialist Congress: N.S. REPORT(Winter 1976/77, Spring 1977, Summer 1977) (Box 1, Folder 3)
- National Socialist Congress: NEWSLETTERJune 1977 (Box 1, Folder 3)
- National Socialist Irish Worker's Party (NSIWP) and National Socialist Party U.K. (NSUPUK): PHOENIX (August-November 1979, December 1980-February 1981) including N.S. News (newsletter of NSIWP and NSPUK) and notes to Phelan. (Box 1, Folder 4)
- National Socialist Movement: NATIONAL SOCIALIST BULLETINMarch-June 1982 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- National Socialist White Worker's Party (NSWWP): correspondence with Phelan and miscellaneous fliers (n.d.-1979), newsletter and WHITE WORKER'S BULLETIN (July 1978, May/June 1979, September/October 1979-January/February 1980) (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Nationalsozialistchen Deutschen Arbeiterpartei-Austlandsorganisation: NS KAMPFRUF(Fall 1976, Spring 1977) (Box 1, Folder 7)
- New Christian Crusade Church(August 1979, June 1980) (Box 1, Folder 7)
- STORMER: THE NEWSLETTER OF THE WHITE REVOLUTION(September 1977, c. 1979) (Box 1, Folder 8)
- THE THUNDERBOLDT: THE WHITE MAN'S VIEWPOINTSeptember 1978 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- White American Political Association (WAPA): information brochure (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Miscellaneous fliers and ephemera: "White Victory" stickers (distributed by the NSWWP) (Box 1, Folder 9)
- anti-black propaganda: "Boat Ticket to Africa" (Box 1, Folder 9)
- underground subversive literature (Box 1, Folder 9)
- altered "Anderson Addresses [altered to 'Undresses'] America" fliers regarding presidential candidate John Anderson(c. 1980) (Box 1, Folder 9)
- fliers regarding Israel and the 1970's oil crisis (Box 1, Folder 9)
- letter in defense of Adolf Hitler, written by James Combs to Glen B. Infield, author of HITLER'S SECRET LIFE (Stein and Day, 1969), printed in CHRISTIAN VANGUARD: THE OFFICIAL PUBLICATION OF THE NEW CHRISTIAN CRUSADE CHURCHn.d. (Box 1, Folder 9)
- flier regarding Kosher products and other anti-Jewish propaganda (Box 1, Folder 9)
- list of stickers/slogans available from NSIWP and NSPUK (Box 1, Folder 9)
- list of available Nazi literature/merchandise (Box 1, Folder 9)
- segregationist flier "Three Steps to Mongrelization" (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Sons of Liberty Booklist (Box 1, Folder 9)
- "Press Release" by Ernst Zundel regarding German rights in Canada and Canadian postal ban against Samisdat Publishers Ltd., Concerned Parents of German Descent, and German-Jewish Historical Commissionc. 1982 (Box 1, Folder 9)
- "White Man Organize: White Guard"(n.d.) (Box 1, Folder 9)
- "Auschwitz: Truth or Lie" (Liberty Bell Publications)1975 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- "A Gallery of Jewish Types" (Sons of Liberty, NSWWP)n.d. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- "The Herald of America" (NSWWP)1979 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- "Historic Testimonial on the Jews!" (National Socialist Movement)n.d. (Box 1, Folder 10)
- THE WHITE PRIMER, by C.W. Bristol: "A Dynamic Racial Analysis of Present Day American from the Viewpoint of the White Majority (Box 1, Folder 11)